Alexandre MAHIEU

190, rue du 14 juillet, 62221 noyelles sous lens (France)

□ 0670072929
 □ mahieualexandre@gmail.com

05 February 2017 application for an internship

Dear Hiring Manager,

Curently in training at PopSchool Lens (France) in the field of web development, I would be really interested by an internship with your company, as part of an Erasmus program during april and may 2017.

I think that this internship would be a real opportunity for me to experiment with a different working system. Also it would be beneficial for me to improve my English skills, as well as my skills as a web developer. This will be essential for my integration into professional life. Moreover, we have generally just one shot to benefit from such a great experience.

I am really interested by back-end development but I am open to any proposition you may offer me.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I'm looking forward to the opportunity of discussing this during the upcoming interview. Sincerely,

Alexandre MAHIEU



PERSONAL INFORMATION

Alexandre MAHIEU

- 190, rue du 14 juillet, 62221 noyelles sous lens (France)
- 670072929
- mahieualexandre@gmail.com
- https://alexandremahieu.github.io/

Sex Male | Date of birth 12/02/1986 | Nationality French

JOB APPLIED FOR

web developer

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Nov 2016-Jun 2017

Titre Professionnel : Développeur web & mobile

EQF level 5

popschool, lens (France)

- How to create Website et application
- IONIC
- CMS (wordpress, prestashop, ...)
- HTML5 & CSS3 (boostrap, sass, ...)
- JAVASCRIP (angularjs, json, jquery, ...)
- RUBY (ruby on rails)
- PHP (symphony, silex, yaml, ...)
- MYSQL (phpmyadmin)
- BASH
- GIT (github, framagit)
- PACKAGE MANAGER (composer, bower)

Nov 2014-May 2015

Titre Professionnel: Commercial

FOF level 4

- Didactif : ANAF, lens (France)
- Learn how to sale products
- B2B prospection
- B2C prospection
- Physical and phoned interviews
- Taking rendez-vous
- Customers fidelisation

...

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2009-Sep 2009

Owner of a bookstore

Alexandre MAHIEU, Cambrai (France)

- Created account with a bank
- Created account with the RSI (state agency)
- Created account with the CCI (state agency)
- Found a place for my shop



Curriculum vitae Alexandre MAHIEU

- Work whit an accounting agency

...

Sep 2009-Oct 2010

Bookstore Manager

Alexandre MAHIEU, cambrai (France)

- Reception, installation and return of merchandises
- Reception of customers
- Management
- Cashing

...

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

French

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEA	WRITING	
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	B2	B1	B1	B1

English

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- Good skills in communication gained through my professional experiments and my association's activity.

Organisational / managerial skills

- Good team-leading skills gained through my professional experiments and my association's activity.

Digital competence

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Satety			
Independent user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Independent user		

Digital competences - Self-assessment grid

I knom how to use:

- LibreOffice / OpenOffice / Microsoft Office
- Trello
- GitHub
- Framagit
- Slack





Alexandre MAHIEU

Mother tongue(s)

French

Other language(s)

English

			English				
	S	elf-as:	sessment of language	skills			
UNDERSTANDING			SPEAKING			WRITING	
Listening	Reading		Spoken interaction	Spoken production		Writing	
B2 Independent user	B2 Independent user		B1 Independent user	B1 Independent user		B1 Independent user	
		Ce	ertificates and diploma	as			
Title		Awarding body		Date		Level*	
_					-		-
	Lin	guisti	c and intercultural ex	perience			
Description			Duration				
	ng or travelling abroad:	- FOSE	DEM 2017 Belgium (Brussels)			- Duratio	וזכ





^{*} Indicate level of the Common European Framework of Reference (CEFR) if specified on certificate or diploma.

The Europeas Language Passport is part of the European Language Portfolio developed by the Council of Europe (www.coe.int/portfolio).

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages - Self-assessment grid

		A1 Basic User	A2 Basic User	B1 Independent user	B2 Independent user	C1 Proficient user	C2 Proficient user
Understanding	Listening	I can understand familiar words and very basic phrases concerning myself, my family and immediate concrete surroundings when people speak slowly and clearly.	I can understand phrases and the highest frequency vocabulary related to areas of most immediate personal relevance (e.g. very basic personal and family information, shopping, local area, employment). I can catch the main point in short, clear, simple messages and announcements.	I can understand the main points of clear standard speech on familiar matters regularly encountered in work, school, leisure, etc. I can understand the main point of many radio or TV programmes on current affairs or topics of personal or professional interest when the delivery is relatively slow and clear.	I can understand extended speech and lectures and follow even complex lines of argument provided the topic is reasonably familiar. I can understand most TV news and current affairs programmes. I can understand the majority of films in standard dialect.	I can understand extended speech even when it is not clearly structured and when relationships are only implied and not signalled explicitly. I can understand television programmes and films without too much effort.	I have no difficulty in understanding any kind of spoken language, whether live or broadcast, even when delivered at fast native speed, provided I have some time to get familiar with the accent.
Unders	Reading	I can understand familiar names, words and very simple sentences, for example on notices and posters or in catalogues.	I can read very short, simple texts. I can find specific, predictable information in simple everyday material such as advertisements, prospectuses, menus and timetables and I can understand short simple personal letters.	I can understand texts that consist mainly of high frequency everyday or job- related language. I can understand the description of events, feelings and wishes in personal letters.	I can read articles and reports concerned with contemporary problems in which the writers adopt particular attitudes or viewpoints. I can understand contemporary literary prose.	I can understand long and complex factual and literary texts, appreciating distinctions of style. I can understand specialised articles and longer technical instructions, even when they do not relate to my field.	I can read with ease virtually all forms of the written language, including abstract, structurally or linguistically complex texts such as manuals, specialised articles and literary works.
Speaking	Spoken interaction]	I can interact in a simple way provided the other person is prepared to repeat or rephrase things at a slower rate of speech and help me formulate what I'm trying to say. I can ask and answer simple questions in areas of immediate need or on very familiar topics.	I can communicate in simple and routine tasks requiring a simple and direct exchange of information on familiar topics and activities. I can handle very short social exchanges, even though I can't usually understand enough to keep the conversation going myself.	I can deal with most situations likely to arise whilst travelling in an area where the language is spoken. I can enter unprepared into conversation on topics that are familiar, of personal interest or pertinent to everyday life (e.g. family, hobbies, work, travel and current events).	I can interact with a degree of fluency and spontaneity that makes regular interaction with native speakers quite possible. I can take an active part in discussion in familiar contexts, accounting for and sustaining my views.	I can express myself fluently and spontaneously without much obvious searching for expressions. I can use language flexibly and effectively for social and professional purposes. I can formulate ideas and opinions with precision and relate my contribution skilfully to those of other speakers.	I can take part effortlessly in any conversation or discussion and have a good familiarity with idiomatic expressions and colloquialisms. I can express myself fluently and convey finer shades of meaning precisely. If I do have a problem I can backtrack and restructure around the difficulty so smoothly that other people are hardly aware of it.
	Spoken production	I can use simple phrases and sentences to describe where I live and people I know.	I can use a series of phrases and sentences to describe in simple terms my family and other people, living conditions, my educational background and my present or most recent job.	I can connect phrases in a simple way in order to describe experiences and events, my dreams, hopes and ambitions. I can briefly give reasons and explanations for opinions and plans. I can narrate a story or relate the plot of a book or film and describe my reactions.	I can present clear, detailed descriptions on a wide range of subjects related to my field of interest. I can explain a viewpoint on a topical issue giving the advantages and disadvantages of various options.	I can present clear, detailed descriptions of complex subjects integrating sub-themes, developing particular points and rounding off with an appropriate conclusion.	I can present a clear, smoothly-flowing description or argument in a style appropriate to the context and with an effective logical structure which helps the recipient to notice and remember significant points.
Writing	Writing	I can write a short, simple postcard, for example sending holiday greetings. I can fill in forms with personal details, for example entering my name, nationality and address on a hotel registration form.	I can write short, simple notes and messages. I can write a very simple personal letter, for example thanking someone for something.	I can write simple connected text on topics which are familiar or of personal interest. I can write personal letters describing experiences and impressions.	I can write clear, detailed text on a wide range of subjects related to my interests. I can write an essay or report, passing on information or giving reasons in support of or against a particular point of view. I can write letters highlighting the personal significance of events and experiences.	I can express myself in clear, well- structured text, expressing points of view at some length. I can write about complex subjects in a letter, an essay or a report, underlining what I consider to be the salient issues. I can select a style appropriate to the reader in mind.	I can write clear, smoothly-flowing text in an appropriate style. I can write complex letters, reports or articles which present a case with an effective logical structure which helps the recipient to notice and remember significant points. I can write summaries and reviews of professional or literary works.

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages (CEF): © Council of Europe